I was asked to come here and speak about creation.
لقد طلب مني المجيء إلى هنا والحديث عن الابداع.
And I only have 15 minutes, and I see they're counting already.
وليس لدي سوى 15 دقيقة ، وأنا أرى انهم بدأوا بالعد.
And I can -- in 15 minutes, I think I can touch only a very rather janitorial branch of creation,
وأستطيع -- في 15 دقيقة ، وأعتقد أنني يمكن أن المس فقط بشكل عام الخلق،
which I call "creativity."
الذي أسميه الإبداع.
Creativity is how we cope with creation.
الإبداع هو كيف يمكننا التعامل مع الخلق.
While creation sometimes seems a bit un-graspable, or even pointless,
وبينما يبدو الخلق في بعض الأحيان غير قابل للإدراك ، أو حتى عبثي،
creativity is always meaningful.
الإبداع دائما ذا مغزى.
See, for instance, in this picture.
انظر ، على سبيل المثال ، في هذه الصورة.
You know, creation is what put that dog in that picture,
أنت تعرف ، الخلق هو ما وضع هذا الكلب في تلك الصورة ،
and creativity is what makes us see a chicken on his hindquarters.
والإبداع هو ما يجعلنا نرى تلك الدجاجه في مؤخرته.
When you think about -- you know, creativity has a lot to do with causality too.
عندما تفكر -- أنت تعرف ، والإبداع فيه الكثير من المنطقية أيضا.
You know, when I was a teenager, I was a creator.
أنت تعرف ، و عندما كنت في سن المراهقة ، كنت مبدعا.
I just did things.
كنت اصنع الاشياء.
Then I became an adult and started knowing who I was,
ثم أصبحت راشدا وأردت ان اعرف من انا،
and tried to maintain that persona -- I became creative.
وحاولت الحفاظ على الشخصية -- أصبحت مبدعا.
It wasn't until I actually did a book and a retrospective exhibition, that I could track exactly --
في الواقع حتى انني لم اتمكن من تأليف كتاب اوحتى من المعرض الاستعادي او المسير بالضبط --
looks like all the craziest things that I had done, all my drinking, all my parties --
تبدو أشد الأشياء الجنونيه التي كنت قد أفعلها ، كل ما عندي من الشرب ، او من كل الأطراف --
they followed a straight line that brings me to the point
اتبع خط مستقيم وهذا يقودني إلى النقطة
that actually I'm talking to you at this moment.
في الواقع أنا أتحدث إليكم في هذه اللحظة
Though it's actually true, you know,
على الرغم من أنه صحيح في الواقع ، كما تعلمون ،
the reason I'm talking to you right now is because I was born in Brazil.
السبب من تحدثي إليكم الآن هو لأنني ولدت في البرازيل.
If I was born in Monterey, probably would be in Brazil.
لقد ولدت في مونتيري ، ربما تكون في البرازيل.
You know, I was born in Brazil and grew up in the '70s
تعلمون ، لقد ولدت في البرازيل ونشأة في السبعينات،
under a climate of political distress,
في ظل مناخ من ضائقه سياسية ،
and I was forced to learn to communicate in a very specific way --
واضطررت لتعلم كيفية التواصل بطريقة محددة جدا --
in a sort of a semiotic black market.
في نوع من السوق السوداء السيميائي.
You couldn't really say what you wanted to say;
أنت لا يمكن أن تقول حقا ما تريد أن تقوله ،
you had to invent ways of doing it.
كان لديك إبتكار طرق للقيام بذلك.
You didn't trust information very much.
لم تكن واثق من الكثير من المعلومات .
That led me to another step of why I'm here today,
التي دفعتني إلى خطوة أخرى لما أنا هو اليوم ،
is because I really liked media of all kinds.
لأنني أحببت حقا وسائل الاعلام من جميع الأنواع.
I was a media junkie, and eventually got involved with advertising.
كنت مدمن وسائل الاعلام ، وفي النهاية حصلت على المشاركة مع الإعلان.
My first job in Brazil
وظيفتي الأولى في البرازيل
was actually to develop a way to improve the readability of billboards,
فعلا في تطوير طريقة لتحسين القراءة من اللوحات الإعلانية ،
and based on speed, angle of approach and actually blocks of text.
وعلى أساس السرعة وزاوية النهج والواقع كـ نص.
It was very -- actually, it was a very good study,
كان جدا -- في الواقع ، كانت دراسة جيدة للغاية ،
and got me a job in an ad agency.
وحصلت لي على وظيفة في وكالة إعلان.
And they also decided that I had to --
وقرروا أيضا أنه يجب --
to give me a very ugly Plexiglas trophy for it.
ان احصل على الكأس الشبكي القبيح جدا لذلك.
And another point -- why I'm here --
وثمة نقطة أخرى -- لماذا أنا هنا --
is that the day I went to pick up the Plexiglas trophy,
هو أن اليوم الذي ذهبت لالتقاط الكأس الزجاج الشبكي،
I rented a tuxedo for the first time in my life,
استأجرت بدلة توكسيدو للمرة الأولى في حياتي ،
picked the thing -- didn't have any friends.
استلام الشيء -- لم يكن لدي أي أصدقاء.
On my way out, I had to break a fight apart.
في طريقي للخارج ، كان علي فك اشتباك.
Somebody was hitting somebody else with brass knuckles.
شخص ما كان يضرب شخص آخر بقبضات حديدية.
They were in tuxedos, and fighting. It was very ugly.
وكانوا في بدلات السهرة ، و كان منظر القتال قبيح جدا.
And also -- advertising people do that all the time -- (Laughter) --
غالبا-- الذين يعملون في الإعلان يفعلوا ذلك في كل وقت -- (ضحك) --
and I -- well, what happened is when I went back, it was on the way back to my car,
كان ذلك جيدا ، لكن ما حدث عندما ذهبت الى الوراء ، في طريق العودة إلى سيارتي ، --وانا
the guy who got hit decided to grab a gun --
الرجل الذي ضرب التقط مسدسا --
I don't know why he had a gun --
أنا لا أعرف لماذا كان لديه مسدس --
and shoot the first person he decided to be his aggressor.
واطلق النار على أول شخص قرر أن يكون المعتدي عليه.
The first person was wearing a black tie, a tuxedo. It was me.
وكان أول شخص يرتدي ربطة عنق سوداء ، و بدلة السهرة. هو انا.
Luckily, it wasn't fatal, as you can all see.
لحسن الحظ ، لم تكن الاصابة قاتلة ، وكما ترون جميعا.
And, even more luckily, the guy said that he was sorry
وأكثر حتى من حسن الحظ ، وقال الرجل انه يشعر بالاسف
and I bribed him for compensation money, otherwise I press charges.
وأنا رشوته مقابل مال التعويض ، وإلا كنت اصر على الاتهامات.
And that's how -- with this money I paid for a ticket to come to the United States in 1983,
وهذه هي الطريقة التي -- مع هذه الأموال دفعت تذكرة للقدوم إلى الولايات المتحدة في عام 1983،
and that's very -- the basic reason I'm talking to you here today:
وهذا أمر بالغ -- السبب الأساسي أنا أتحدث إليكم هنا اليوم.
because I got shot. (Laughter) (Applause)
لأني اصبت بطلق ناري. (ضحك) (تصفيق)
Well, when I started working with my own work, I decided that I shouldn't do images.
حسنا ، عندما بدأت عملي، قررت ان لا اشتغل بالصور.
You know, I became -- I took this very iconoclastic approach.
أنت تعرف ، أنا أصبحت -- بهذا النهج متمرد جدا.
Because when I decided to go into advertising, I wanted to do --
لأنه عندما قررت العمل في الإعلانات، وأردت أن أفعل --
I wanted to airbrush naked people on ice, for whiskey commercials,
أردت أن ابخ الناس العاريه على الجليد ، للإعلانات الويسكي،
that's what I really wanted to do. (Laughter)
هذا ما أردت حقا أن أفعله.
But I -- they didn't let me do it, so I just -- you know,
لكن -- لم يسمحوا لي بذلك ، لذلك أنا فقط -- أنتم تعرفون،
they would only let me do other things.
فإنهم سمحوا لي فقط أن أفعل أشياء أخرى.
But I wasn't into selling whiskey; I was into selling ice.
لكن لم أكن بائع ويسكي، كنت أبيع الثلج.
The first works were actually objects.
أولا عملت في الواقع على الكائنات.
It was kind of a mixture of found object, product design and advertising.
وكان نوع من مزيج من الكائن وجدت ، وتصميم المنتجات والدعاية.
And I called them relics.
ودعوتها بالاثار.
They were displayed first at Stux Gallery in 1983.
تم عرضها وهي الأولى في معرض Stux في عام 1983.
This is the clown skull.
وهذا هي جمجمة مهرج.
Is a remnant of a race of -- a very evolved race of entertainers.
من بقايا عرق -- عرق فنانين متطور جدا.
They lived in Brazil, long time ago. (Laughter)
عاشوا في البرازيل ، ومنذ وقت طويل. (ضحك)
This is the Ashanti joystick.
وهذا هو عصا التحكم أشانتي.
Unfortunately, it has become obsolete because it was designed for Atari platform.
لسوء الحظ ، فقد عفا عليها الزمن لأنها كانت مصممة لمنصة أتاري.
A Playstation II is in the works, maybe for the next TED I'll bring it.
وبلاي ستيشن الثاني مازال يعمل ، وربما سأحضره لجلسة TED القادمة.
The rocking podium. (Laughter)
المنصة الهزازة.
This is the pre-Columbian coffeemaker. (Laughter)
وهذا هو صانع القهوة من عصر ما قبل كولومبوس.
Actually, the idea came out of an argument that I had at Starbucks,
في الواقع ، جاءت فكرة للخروج من جدال في ستاربكس،
that I insisted that I wasn't having Colombian coffee;
كنت أصر على أن البن الذي نتناوله لم يكن كولومبي،
the coffee was actually pre-Columbian.
وكان البن في الواقع ما قبل كولومبوس.
The Bonsai table.
الطاولة البونساية.
The entire Encyclopedia Britannica bound in a single volume, for travel purposes.
وكامل موسوعة بريتانيكا ملزمة في مجلد واحد ، لأغراض السفر.
And the half tombstone, for people who are not dead yet.
وشاهد نصف القبر ، للأشخاص الذين لم يمتوا بعد.
I wanted to take that into the realm of images,
أردت أن أخذ ذلك الى عالم الصور،
and I decided to make things that had the same identity conflicts.
وأنا قررت أن أجعل الأشياء التي لها نفس الهوية تتصارع.
So I decided to do work with clouds.
لذا قررت ان اعمل مع الغيوم.
Because clouds can mean anything you want.
لأن الغيوم يمكن ان تعني أي شيء تريده.
But now I wanted to work in a very low-tech way,
ولكن أريد الآن أن العمل بطريقة منخفضة التقنية جدا،
so something that would mean at the same time
ذلك شيء وهذا يعني في نفس الوقت
a lump of cotton, a cloud and Durer's praying hands --
قطعة من القطن ، سحابة دورير واليدين في الصلاة --
although this looks a lot more like Mickey Mouse's praying hands.
على الرغم من أن هذا يبدو كثيرا مثل يدي ميكي ماوس في الصلاة.
But I was still, you know -- this is a kitty cloud.
ولكن كنت لا أزال ، كما تعلمون -- وهذا هي سحابة كيتي.
They're called "Equivalents," after Alfred Stieglitz's work.
تدعى المعادل ، مقتبسة عن عمل لألفريد شتيجلتز.
"The Snail."
"الحلزون".
But I was still working with sculpture,
ولكن كنت لاأزال أعمل على النحت،
and I was really trying to go flatter and flatter.
وكنت أحاول حقا أن أتملق و أتملق.
"The Teapot."
"إبريق الشاي".
I had a chance to go to Florence, in -- I think it was '94,
سنحت لي الفرصة للذهاب إلى فلورنسا ، في -- اعتقد انه كان '94
and I saw Ghiberti's "Door of Paradise."
وشاهدت Ghiberti في "باب الجنة".
And he did something that was very tricky.
قام بعمل صعب للغاية.
He put together two different media from different periods of time.
وضع معا اثنين من وسائل الإعلام المختلفة من فترات زمنية مختلفة.
First, he got an age-old way of making it, which was relief,
أولا ، حصل على وسيلة قديمة من صنعه ، وكانت راحة،
and he worked this with three-point perspective, which was brand-new technology at the time.
وكان يعمل مع هذا المنظور من ثلاث نقاط ، والتي كانت تكنولوجيا العلامة التجارية الجديدة في ذلك الوقت.
And it's totally overkill.
وانها مبالغة مطلقة.
And your eye doesn't know which level to read.
وعينك لا تعرف من أي مستوى تقرأ.
And you become trapped into this kind of representation.
وتصبح محاصر في هذا النوع من التمثيل.
So I decided to make these very simple renderings,
وهكذا قررت أن أجعل هذه الاداء بسيط جدا ،
that at first they are taken as a line drawing --
في البداية أن أخذ على أنها رسم خط.
you know, something that's very -- and then I did it with wire.
أنتم تعرفون ، هذا الشيء جدا -- ثم أنا عملت هذا مع سلك.
The idea was to -- because everybody overlooks white -- like pencil drawings, you know?
وكانت الفكرة -- لأن الجميع يغفل الأبيض -- مثل رسومات قلم رصاص ، هل تعلم؟
And they would look at it -- "Ah, it's a pencil drawing."
وانهم نظروا في الأمر -- آه ، انها الرسم بقلم الرصاص.
Then you have this double take and see that it's actually something that existed in time.
ثم لديك هذه الطريقة المزدوجة ونرى أنها في الواقع كانت موجودة في الماضي.
It had a physicality,
وكانت محسوسة ،
and you start going deeper and deeper into sort of narrative
وتبدأ الذهاب أعمق وأعمق في نوع من السرد
that goes this way, towards the image. So this is "Monkey with Leica."
بهذه الطريقة ، لهذه الصورة. كما هو "القرد مع لايكا".
"Relaxation."
"استرخاء".
"Fiat Lux."
"لوكس فيات".
And the same way the history of representation
وبنفس الطريقة ، تاريخ التمثيل
evolved from line drawings to shaded drawings.
تطورت من خط الرسومات إلى رسومات مظللة.
And I wanted to deal with other subjects.
وكنت أرغب في التعامل مع مواضيع أخرى.
I started taking that into the realm of landscape,
أنا بدأت في اتخاذ ذلك في مجال المناظر الطبيعية ،
which is something that's almost a picture of nothing.
وهو أمر يكاد يكون صورة من لا شيء.
I made these pictures called "Pictures of Thread,"
اخذت هذه الصورة و دعوتها صورة الخيط ،
and I named them after the amount of yards that I used to represent each picture.
وأسميتها حسب مقدار الخيوط التي استعملتها لتمثيل كل صورة.
These always end up being a photograph at the end,
هذه دائما في نهاية المطاف تكون صورة في النهاية ،
or more like an etching in this case.
أو أكثر مثل النقش في هذه الحالة.
So this is a lighthouse.
لذا، هذا فنار.
This is "6,500 Yards," after Corot. "9,000 Yards," after Gerhard Richter.
هذا هو "6500 ياردة ،" من كورو. "9000 ياردة ،" من غيرهارد ريشتر.
And I don't know how many yards, after John Constable.
وأنا لا أعرف كم ياردة ، من جون كونستابل.
Departing from the lines, I decided to tackle the idea of points,
بالابتعاد عن خطوط ، قررت معالجة فكرة بالنقاط ،
like which is more similar to the type of representation that we find in photographs themselves.
هو أكثر مماثلة إلى نوع التمثيل التي نجدها في الصور ذاتها.
I had met a group of children in the Caribbean island of Saint Kitts,
كنت قد التقيت مجموعة من الأطفال في منطقة البحر الكاريبي جزيرة سانت كيتس ،
and I did work and play with them.
و عملت وللعبت معهم.
I got some photographs from them.
و حصلت على بعض صورهم.
Upon my arrival in New York, I decided --
عند وصولي الى نيويورك ، قررت --
they were children of sugar plantation workers.
ان الأطفال هم ابناء عمال مزارع السكر.
And by manipulating sugar over a black paper, I made portraits of them.
و من خلال التلاعب بالسكر على ورقة سوداء ، رسمت صورهم.
These are -- (Applause) --
وهذه هي -- (تصفيق) --
Thank you. This is "Valentina, the Fastest."
شكرا لكم. هذا هو "فالنتينا ، الأسرع".
It was just the name of the child,
كان مجرد اسم للطفل ،
with the little thing you get to know of somebody that you meet very briefly.
مع الشيء القليل الذي تعرف على شخص ما أن تلتقي لفترة وجيزة جدا.
"Valicia."
"Valicia".
"Jacynthe."
"Jacynthe".
But another layer of representation was still introduced.
ولكن طبقة أخرى من التمثيل تقدم.
Because I was doing this while I was making these pictures,
لأنني كنت اقوم بهذا بينما كنت اعمل هذه الصور ،
I realized that I could add still another thing
أدركت أنه مازال بالامكان إضافة شيء آخر
I was trying to make a subject --
كنت أحاول أن جعل موضوع --
something that would interfere with the themes,
شيء من شأنه أن يتدخل في المواضيع ،
so chocolate is very good, because it has --
حتى الشوكولاته جيدة جدا ، لأنها
it brings to mind ideas that go from scatology to romance.
-- يعيد إلى الأذهان الأفكار التي تذهب من علم البراز إلى الرومانسية.
And so I decided to make these pictures,
وهكذا قررت أن اجعل هذه الصور ،
and they were very large, so you had to walk away from it to be able to see them.
وأنها كبيرة جدا ، لذلك كان عليك أن تمشي بعيدا لتكون قادرا على رؤيتها.
So they're called "Pictures of Chocolate."
حتى انها دعيت صور الشوكولاته.
Freud probably could explain chocolate better than I. He was the first subject.
فرويد يمكن على الأرجح أن يفسر أفضل مني الشوكولاته. كان هو الموضوع أولا.
And Jackson Pollock also.
وجاكسون بولوك أيضا.
Pictures of crowds are particularly interesting,
صور الحشود هي مثيرة للاهتمام بشكل خاص ،
because, you know, you go to that --
لأنه ، كما تعلمون ، أن تذهب إلى ذلك --
you try to figure out the threshold with something you can define very easily,
انت تحاول معرفة عتبة شيء يمكنك بسهولة تحديده جدا،
like a face, goes into becoming just a texture.
مثل الوجه ، و الذي يمكن أن يصبح مجرد الملمس.
"Paparazzi."
"المصورون الصحفيون".
I used the dust at the Whitney Museum to render some pieces of their collection.
استخدمت الغبار في متحف ويتني لتقديم بعض القطع من مجموعتهم.
And I picked minimalist pieces because they're about specificity.
اخترت أنا قطع الحد الأدنى لانه لها خصوصية.
And you render this with the most non-specific material,
وأنت تعيد هذا مع معظم المواد غير المحددة ،
which is dust itself.
وهو الغبار نفسه.
Like, you know, you have the skin particles of every single museum visitor.
مثل ، كما تعلمون ، لديك جزيئات الجلد من كل زوار المتحف.
They do a DNA scan of this, they will come up with a great mailing list.
و بتحليل الحمض النووي لهذا الغبار ، سوف تنتج قائمة بريدية كبيرة.
This is Richard Serra.
وهذا هو ريتشارد سيرا.
I bought a computer, and [they] told me it had millions of colors in it.
اشتريت جهاز كمبيوتر ، و [هم] وقال لي انه يحتوي الملايين من الألوان.
You know an artist's first response to this is, who counted it? You know?
أنت تعرف استجابة الفنان الأولى لهذا ، من الذي احصى الالوان؟ هل تعرف؟
And I realized that I never worked with color,
وأدركت أنني لم اعمل مع اللون ،
because I had a hard time controlling the idea of single colors.
لانه كان لدي صعوبة في السيطرة على فكرة واحدة في الألوان.
But once they're applied to numeric structure,
ولكن تطبيقها في معظمه في بنية رقمية ،
then you can feel more comfortable.
ثم يمكنك أن تشعر براحة أكبر.
So the first time I worked with colors was by making these mosaics of Pantone swatches.
لذا في المرة الأولى التي عملت مع الألوان من خلال صنع هذه الفسيفساء للبانتيون.
They end up being very large pictures,
و في نهاية تصبح الصور كبيرة جدا،
and I photographed with a very large camera --
وصورت بكاميرا كبيرة جدا --
an 8x10 camera.
كاميرا ثمانية في 10 .
So you can see the surface of every single swatch --
يمكن حتى تشاهد سطح كل قطعة على حدى --
like in this picture of Chuck Close.
في مثل هذه الصورة من تشك تشاك.
And you have to walk very far to be able to see it.
وعليك أن تسير شوطا بعيدا جدا لأن تكون قادرا على رؤية ذلك.
Also, the reference to Gerhard Richter's use of color charts --
أيضا ، الإشارة إلى استخدام الرسوم البيانية مخططات غيرهارد ريشتر --
and the idea also entering another realm of representation that's very common to us today,
وأيضا فكرة دخول عالم التمثيل آخر أن من الشائع للغاية بالنسبة لنا اليوم ،
which is the bit map.
والذي هو خريطة بت.
I ended up narrowing the subject to Monet's "Haystacks."
انتهى بي الأمر الى اختصار هذا الموضوع إلى أكوام تبن مونيه.
This is something I used to do as a joke --
وهذا شيء يمكن ان تفعله على سبيل المزاح --
you know, make -- the same like -- Robert Smithson's "Spiral Jetty" --
تعلمون ، جعل -- النفس مثل -- روبرت سميثسون في "دوامة جيتي"
and then leaving traces, as if it was done on a tabletop.
وترك آثار ذلك ، كما كان على الطاولة.
I tried to prove that he didn't do that thing in the Salt Lake.
حاولت ان اثبت انه لم يفعل هذا الشيء في سولت لايك.
But then, just doing the models, I was trying to explore the relationship
ولكن بعد ذلك ، مجرد عمل النماذج ، محاولا استكشاف العلاقة
between the model and the original.
بين النموذج و الأصل.
And I felt that I would have to actually go there and make some earthworks myself.
وشعرت أنني يجب أن أذهب هناك في الواقع وتقديم بعض أعمال الحفر نفسي.
I opt for very simple line drawings -- kind of stupid looking.
أنا اختيار خط رسومات بسيطة للغاية -- نوع ما مظهر غبي.
And at the same time, I was doing these very large constructions,
و في نفس الوقت ، كنت اقوم به هذه المنشآت كبيرة جدا ،
being 150 meters away.
يمتد لمسافة 150 متر.
Now I would do very small ones, which would be like --
الآن وأود أن انجز اعمال الصغيرة جدا ، والتي ستكون مثل --
but under the same light, and I would show them together,
ولكن تحت نفس الضوء ، ووضعهم معا ،
so the viewer would have to really figure it out what one he was looking.
حتى أن المشاهد يجب أن يتحقق على اي واحد كان ينظر.
I wasn't interested in the very large things, or in the small things.
لم أكن مهتما بالأشياء كبيرة جدا ، أو الأشياء الصغيرة.
I was more interested in the things in between,
كنت مهتما أكثر في الأمور البين بين ،
you know, because you can leave an enormous range for ambiguity there.
تعلمون ، لأنه يمكنك ترك مساحة هائلة للغموض هناك.
This is like you see -- the size of a person over there.
وهذا هو كأنك تراه -- حجم شخص هناك.
This is a pipe.
وهذا هو أنبوب.
A hanger.
علاقة الثياب.
And this is another thing that I did -- you know working
وهذا هو آخر شيء فعلته -- كما تعلمون العمل
-- everybody loves to watch somebody draw,
-- الجميع يحب مشاهدة رسم شخص ما ،
but not many people have a chance to watch somebody draw in --
ولكن ليس الكثير من الناس لديهم فرصة لمشاهدة شخص في رسم --
a lot of people at the same time, to evidence a single drawing.
الكثير من الناس في نفس الوقت ، لاثبات رسم واحد.
And I love this work,
وأنا أحب هذا العمل ،
because I did these cartoonish clouds over Manhattan for a period of two months.
عملت تلك الغيوم الكرتونية فوق مانهاتن لأكثر من شهرين.
And it was quite wonderful, because I had an interest -- an early interest -- in theater,
وكانت رائعة جدا ، لأن لي مصلحة -- مصلحة في وقت مبكر -- في المسرح ،
that's justified on this thing.
لتبرير هذا الشيء.
In theater, you have the character and the actor in the same place,
في المسرح ، لديك حرف والفاعل في نفس المكان ،
trying to negotiate each other in front of an audience.
يحاول التفاوض بعضهم البعض أمام جمهور.
And in this, you'd have like a --
و في هذا ، وكنت قد مثل --
something that looks like a cloud, and it is a cloud at the same time.
شيء يشبه سحابة ، وإنه سحابة في نفس الوقت.
So they're like perfect actors.
حتى انهم مثل الممثلين المثاليين.
My interest in acting, especially bad acting, goes a long way.
اهتمامي في التمثيل ، ولا سيما السيئ ، قطع شوطا طويلا.
Actually, I once paid like 60 dollars
في الواقع ، أن تدفع مرة واحدة مثل 60 دولار
to see a very great actor to do a version of "King Lear,"
لرؤية الفنان الكبير جدا الذي قدم نسخة من الملك لير ،
and I felt really robbed, because by the time the actor started being King Lear,
وشعرت بانني سلبت حقا ، لأن في الوقت الذي بدأ الممثل يؤدي دور الملك لير ،
he stopped being the great actor that I had paid money to see.
توقف عن ان يكون الفنان الكبير الذي دفعت المال لاشاهده.
On the other hand, you know, I paid like three dollars, I think --
من ناحية أخرى ، كما تعلمون ، لقد دفعت ثلاثة دولارات ، كما أعتقد --
and I went to a warehouse in Queens
وذهبت الى مستودع في كوينز
to see a version of "Othello" by an amateur group.
لرؤية نسخة من عطيل من قبل مجموعة الهواة.
And it was quite fascinating, because you know the guy --
وكانت رائعة جدا ، لأنك تعرف الرجل --
his name was Joey Grimaldi --
واسمه جوي غريمالدي --
he impersonated the Moorish general
مثل القائد العام المغاربي
-- you know, for the first three minutes he was really that general,
-- كما تعلمون ، خلال الدقائق الثلاث الأولى كان حقا أن القائد ،
and then he went back into plumber, he worked as a plumber, so --
وبعد ذلك عاد إلى سباك ، كان يعمل سباك ، لذلك --
plumber, general, plumber, general --
السباك العام ، سباك ، العام --
so for three dollars, I saw two tragedies for the price of one.
حتى بثلاثة دولارات ، رأيت اثنين من المآسي بسعر واحد.
See, I think it's not really about impression,
انظر ، وأعتقد أنه ليست حقا عن الانطباع ،
making people fall for a really perfect illusion,
جعل الناس يسقوطون في وهم المثالية حقا ،
as much as it is to make -- I usually work at the lowest threshold of visual illusion.
بقدر ما جعل هو -- وعادة ما يعمل على أدنى حد من الوهم البصري.
Because it's not about fooling somebody,
لأنها ليست حول خداع حول شخص ما ،
it's actually giving somebody a measure of their own belief:
انها فعلا اعطاء شخص ما مقياسا لاعتقادهم الخاصة :
how much you want to be fooled.
كم من الاستغفال تريد.
That's why we pay to go to magic shows and things like that.
وهذا هو السبب الذي من اجله ندفع للذهاب إلى العروض السحرية واشياء من هذا القبيل.
Well, I think that's it.
حسنا ، أعتقد أن هذا كل شيء.
My time is nearly up.
وقتي على وشك الانتهاء.
Thank you very much.
لكم جزيل الشكر.